Privacy Policy
==============

Pixiv Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively, “we”, “us”, “our”, etc.) uses Personal Information (as defined in the following article) of customers, transaction counterparties, applicants for employment with us, our employees, etc. (“Customers etc.”, “you”, “your”, etc.) in the course of our business activities.

As a company that provides a variety of content and services, we believe it to be an important responsibility to comply with the Act on the Protection of Personal Information (APPI) and handle Personal Information appropriately. We have established this Privacy Policy as our policy for handling Personal Information of Customers etc., and handle information of Customers etc. in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Definitions**
===============

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, Personal Information and Personal Data are defined as follows.

What is Personal Information
----------------------------

Personal information is information about a living individual that falls under any of the following categories

*   Information that can identify a specific individual by name, address, date of birth, gender, occupation, telephone number, e-mail address, etc., contained therein.

*   Information that by itself does not identify a specific individual, but can be easily cross-referenced with other information to identify a specific individual.

*   Items containing personal identification code (Article 2(2) of the APPI).

What is Personal Data
---------------------

Personal data means Personal Information that constitutes a “Personal Information database, etc.” (Article 16(1) of the APPI).

Scope of this Privacy Policy and User Data Obtained
===================================================

We obtain the following information including Personal Information (“User Data”) from Customers etc.

(1) Information items relating to Users (“Users”) of various services provided by us (“Our Services”)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

When you use Our Services, we obtain the information you register with us, as well as any identifying information etc. that you generate. This includes the following information:

Examples: name, address, postal code, telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth, age, gender, information associated with the account, country and region, language, device information, IP address and other information, information related to payment (including information related to purchases and sales), profile information, etc.

(2) Information items relating to contests etc. entrants
--------------------------------------------------------

When you enter a contest or campaign (“Contest etc.”) conducted by us, we will obtain the information you provide to us.

Examples: name, address, postal code, telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth, school name, account information, transfer account information, etc.

(3) Information items relating to transaction counterparties
------------------------------------------------------------

We obtain information relating to transaction counterparties, including the following items:

Examples: name, address, postal code, telephone number, e-mail address, company name, transfer account information, etc.)

(4) Information items relating to applicants for employment
-----------------------------------------------------------

In the course of our recruitment activities, we obtain information from applicants for employment, including the following items:

Examples: name, address, postal code, telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth, age, educational background, work history, qualifications held, and other information provided by the applicant to us or obtained by us at the time of recruitment, such as information on the applicant’s resume and CV, reference check details, etc.

(5) Information items relating to employees
-------------------------------------------

We obtain information about our employees, including the following information.

Examples: name, address, postal code, telephone number, e-mail address, date of birth, age, educational background, work history, information on qualifications held, other information on resume and CV, contents of reference checks, information required to be obtained by laws and regulations, information etc. relating to evaluations

Purposes of Use
===============

We use the information we obtain from Customers etc. for the following purposes

Purpose of use of User Data concerning Users of Our Services
------------------------------------------------------------

(1) To ensure the stable operation of Our Services
--------------------------------------------------

*   To create User accounts
*   For User authentication
*   To facilitate transactions in Our Services by us or Users
*   To facilitate transactions between Users
*   To respond to inquiries
*   To investigate the use of Our Services, such as whether there is any prohibited activity, unauthorized access, or other illegal or unauthorized activity
*   For security protection and fraud prevention
*   To perform delivery procedures when such procedures occur
*   To contact Users to request consent for the handling of Personal Information
*   To generate anonymized or Pseudonymized Personal Information for the purpose of producing statistical information
*   To produce statistical information and make it available to Users
*   To apply for insurance contracts relating to goods entered into a warehouse when using a warehouse service
*   To facilitate other of Our Services

(2) To facilitate the smooth processing of payments when such payments occur in Our Services
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

*   To execute payments (including subsequent refund processing and cancellation)

*   To prevent fraudulent payments

*   To provide necessary information to companies that provide payment-related services (“Payment-Related Companies”) in order to investigate transactions suspected of being fraudulent

*   To respond to requests from Payment-Related Companies to investigate fraudulent transactions etc.

*   To respond to inquiries regarding payments

(3) To analyze and improve Our Services, to provide better services, and to confirm the usage of Our Services
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

*   To conduct surveys for Users

*   To send rewards to Users who respond to surveys

*   To create statistical information from survey results and usage history of Our Services, and to use such information as a reference for the development of Our Services

*   o provide personalized content and advertising based on usage history of Our Services

*   To conduct promotional activities according to User segments

*   To improve Our Services

(4) For our marketing activities and to display advertisements tailored to Users
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

*   To distribute advertisements and information about us and our transaction counterparties to Users

*   To send information on campaigns, events, etc. conducted by us

(5) Purpose of use of User Data concerning entrants to contests, etc. conducted on Our Services by us or our transaction counterparties
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

*   To ensure the smooth operation and implementation of contests, etc.

*   To send prize money and prizes to winners of contests, etc.

*   To provide User Data necessary for the selection of winners and prize winners to our transaction counterparties

*   To respond to inquiries regarding contests, etc.

Purpose of use of User Data concerning our transaction counterparties
---------------------------------------------------------------------

*   To perform agreements with transaction counterparties

*   To manage payments and income relating to transaction counterparties

*   To carry out our sales activities

Purpose of use of User Data relating to our recruitment activities
------------------------------------------------------------------

*   To screen applicants for employment (including reference checks)

*   To provide information to, contact, and notify applicants for employment

*   To provide information on employment opportunities to persons seeking employment with us

*   To contact applicants for employment who are referred by our employees

*   To generate anonymized or Pseudonymized Personal Information for the purpose of producing statistical information

Purpose of use of User Data concerning our employees
----------------------------------------------------

(1) Purposes of use for User Data that falls under “Personal Information”

We use this information for labor management, benefits, etc., including personnel affairs, attendance, payroll, health or injury / illness conditions, or for various procedures related to employment and employment management (including disclosure within our group companies for business communication, education and training, etc.).

(2) Purpose of use of User Data that falls under “Specific Personal Information”

(i) “Specific Personal Information” in this item refers to Personal Information of our officers and employees (collectively, “Employees etc.”) and their dependents, etc. that relates to the personal numbers and Specific Personal Information of Employees etc. and their dependents.

(ii) We use such Specific Personal Information to perform the following operations.

*   Administrative work relating withholding tax

*   Administrative work relating to preparation of application forms for exemption for dependents, deduction for insurance premiums, and special exemption for spouse of employment income earner

*   Administrative work relating preparation of tax returns relating to retirement income

*   Administrative work relating individual inhabitant tax

*   Administrative work relating to employment insurance

*   Administrative work relating to health insurance and employees’ pension insurance

*   Notification of National Pension Plan No. 3 insured persons

*   Administrative work relating to preparation of payment records for remuneration, fees, etc.

(iii) We do not provide Specific Personal Information to any third party, except in cases permitted under the Act on the Use of Numbers to Identify a Specific Individual in Administrative Procedures.

Entrustment of Operations Involving Personal Information
========================================================

We may entrust all or part of the operations handling Personal Data to third parties to the extent necessary to achieve the “Purposes of Use.” Such entrustment may include companies outside of Japan. [The companies](https://policies.pixiv.net/en/privacy/outofjapan.html) to which we currently entrust operations outside of Japan are listed .

We select service providers that are found to handle Personal Data appropriately and ensure that Personal Data is properly managed when contracting with such service providers.

Sharing of Personal Data
========================

We share your Personal Data as follows. Please note that for the purpose of sharing, your Personal Data will be shared only with our group companies to the extent necessary, and not necessarily with all of our group companies.

In the event that laws, regulations, guidelines, etc. apply to the provision of Personal Data, we will comply with such laws and regulations etc. and take appropriate measures, and will not share Personal Data except as permitted by laws and regulations.

(1) Items of Personal Data to be shared
---------------------------------------

*   Items registered with us by Users or transaction counterparties

*   Identification information of Users and transaction counterparties

*   Any and all items registered by the Users on the Services

*   information about our employees

(2) Scope of joint Users
------------------------

*   Pixiv Inc.

*   Incolore Corporation

*   Pixiv Marketing, Inc.

*   Pixiv Technologies, Inc.

*   Pixiv Qualia Inc.

(3) Purpose of use in case of sharing
-------------------------------------

Please refer to the [“Purposes of Use”](#purposes_of_use) section of this Privacy Policy for the purposes for which Personal Data may be shared.

(4) Person responsible for sharing
----------------------------------

4-23-5 Sendagaya, Shibuya-ku, Tokyo

Pixiv Inc.

Yasuhiro Niwa

**Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties**
===============================================

Cases of provision of Personal Data to third parties
----------------------------------------------------

In principle, we do not provide Personal Data to third parties (provision of Personal Data to a third party is hereinafter referred to as “Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties”); provided, however, that this excludes the cases set forth in the paragraphs of this Article and the cases set forth in the following items.

*   Cases where we provide Personal Information to third parties as specified in the items of Article 27(5) of the APPI

*   Cases where we have obtained the prior consent of the Customer etc., to provide the information to third parties

*   Cases where required by laws and regulations

*   Cases where it is necessary for the protection of the life, body, or property of an individual and it is difficult to obtain the consent of the individual

*   Cases where there is a specific need for improving public health or to promote the sound development of children and it is difficult to obtain the consent of the individual

*   Cases where it is necessary to cooperate with a national agency, a local government, or an individual or entity entrusted by either a national agency or local government to execute affairs prescribed by laws and regulations, and in which obtaining the consent of the individual is likely to impede the execution of such affairs

*   Cases where we receive an inquiry from a police officer, public prosecutor, public prosecutor’s assistant, national tax official, drug enforcement official, bar association, court, or other party with legal authority to make an inquiry, or when we determine that an emergency evacuation or self-defense is required.

Provision to payment companies etc. and transfer outside Japan
--------------------------------------------------------------

In order to detect or prevent payment execution and payment abuse, we may provide payment-related User Data to payment-related companies and companies that actually perform payments through payment-related companies (“Payment Companies”; payment-related companies and payment companies are collectively referred to as “Payment Companies etc.”). If a Payment Company etc. used by a Customer etc. is located outside of Japan, this information may be transferred to a third party outside of Japan. In such cases, please check [here](https://policies.pixiv.net/en/privacy/outofjapan.html) for information on the transfer destination.

Security Control Systems
========================

When handling Personal Information, we take the following strict security measures in accordance with internal rules to prevent loss, falsification, and leakage of Personal Data.

Establishment of basic policy
-----------------------------

In order to ensure the proper handling of User Data that falls under the category of Personal Information, we will establish and review as necessary matters such as compliance with related laws, regulations, guidelines etc., matters concerning security control measures, and the contact point for handling complaints, in this Privacy Policy.

Establishment of handling rules for security control of Personal Data
---------------------------------------------------------------------

For each stage of obtainment, use, storage, provision, deletion, etc., we will establish rules regarding handling methods, responsible persons, persons in charge, and their duties, etc., and review them as necessary.

Organizational security control measures
----------------------------------------

In addition to appointing a person responsible for the handling of Personal Data, we will clarify the employees who handle Personal Data and the scope of Personal Data handled by such employees, and establish a system for reporting to the person responsible in the event that we become aware of facts or signs of any violation of laws or handling rules.

Personnel security control measures
-----------------------------------

We educate our employees on the matters to keep in mind regarding the handling of Personal Data.

Physical security control measures
----------------------------------

We take the following measures for physical security control:

*   Management of Personal Data handling areas, etc.
*   Measures to be taken in the event of theft of equipment or electronic media, etc.
*   Prevention of leakage etc. when carrying electronic media, etc.
*   Establishment and implementation of rules for deletion of Personal Data and disposal of equipment, electronic media, etc.

Technical security control measures
-----------------------------------

We take the following measures for technical security control:

*   Setting User and management categories for Personal Data and access controls
*   Controlling access privileges to Personal Data
*   Ensuring the security of Personal Data
*   Monitoring the operation of information systems that handle Personal Data
*   Monitoring information systems that handle Personal Data

Handling of Pseudonymized Personal Information
==============================================

Creation of Pseudonymized Personal Information
----------------------------------------------

When we create Pseudonymized Personal Information (information about an individual obtained by processing Personal Information by taking measures specified in laws and regulations so that the individual cannot be identified unless the information is cross-referenced with other information), we will process the information appropriately in accordance with the standards set forth in laws and regulations.

Security control measures for Pseudonymized Personal Information etc.
---------------------------------------------------------------------

We will take security control measures for Pseudonymized Personal Information in accordance with the provisions of laws and regulations.

Handling of Pseudonymized Personal Information
----------------------------------------------

We handle Pseudonymized Personal Information that is Personal Information in accordance with the following:

*   The information will be used within the scope set forth in the “Purposes of Use” section of this Privacy Policy.

*   If the information is to be used for purposes other than those described in the “Purposes of Use” section of this Privacy Policy, we will publicly announce the new purposes of use before using the information.

*   When there is no longer a need to use the Pseudonymized Personal Information, we will make efforts to delete it without delay.

*   Pseudonymized Personal Information will not be provided to third parties, except when required by laws and regulations or when provided to service providers to the extent necessary for the performance of our business; provided, however, that this excludes cases where the information is provided as a result of the succession of business due to a merger or other reasons.

*   Pseudonymized Personal Information will not be cross-referenced with other information for the purpose of identifying the individual to whom the original Personal Information pertains.

Handling of Anonymized Information
==================================

Creation of anonymized information
----------------------------------

When we create anonymized information (information about individuals obtained by processing Personal Information so that specific individuals cannot be identified through measures prescribed by laws and regulations, and such Personal Information cannot be restored), we will take the following measures.

*   Appropriate processing in accordance with the standards set forth in laws and regulations.

*   Taking security control measures to prevent leakage, etc. of deleted information and information on processing methods in accordance with the standards set forth in laws and regulations./li>

*   Public announcement of the items of information contained in the anonymized information created

*   Not taking any action to identify an individual whose Personal Information was the source for the creation of the information

*   When anonymized information is obtained from a third party, information regarding the deleted information or the method of processing shall not be obtained or cross-referenced with other information for the purpose of identifying the individual to whom the original Personal Information pertains.

Items included in Anonymized Information
----------------------------------------

The items include the items of User Data that we hold with respect to Customers etc.

Provision of anonymized information to third parties
----------------------------------------------------

The purposes for which anonymized information created by us is provided to third parties, the items included in the anonymized information, and the method of provision are as follows.

*   Purpose

To create statistical information for our affiliated companies or research institutes, etc.

*   Items included in anonymized information to be provided to third parties

The items listed in “Items included in anonymized information” above are included.

*   Method of provision

Data files are encrypted and provided by secure means.

Procedures for Requests Regarding Personal Data and Records on Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties
==========================================================================================================

If, with respect to Personal Data in our possession (meaning “Personal Data” as defined in Article 16(4) of the APPI that we currently possesses and is authorized to disclose; “Retained Personal Data”) or records of provision of such Personal Data to third parties (“Records on Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties”), we receive a request from a data subject (meaning a request for disclosure of Personal Data or Records on Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties, correction, deletion, suspension of use, or erasure of Personal Data, or suspension of provision to third parties; collectively, "Disclosure etc."); we will respond appropriately in accordance with laws and regulations; provided, however, that if we are unable to verify the identity of the customer etc., we will not comply with the request.

Requests for disclosure of Personal Data and Records on Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

With respect to Personal Data, we will disclose all or part of the Personal Data only if it is included in the Retained Personal Data, and with respect to Records on Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties, only if Retained Personal Data has been provided to a third party, in accordance with laws and regulations; provided, however, that the following cases are excluded from disclosure:

*   Cases where the data does not fall under Retained Personal Data

*   Cases where we are only entrusted with the Personal Data and do not have the authority to disclose it

*   Cases where the disclosure falls under any of the following items as stipulated in Article 33 of the APPI
    
    *   Cases where disclosure may harm the life, body, property, or other rights or interests of the person in question or a third party
    
    *   Cases where there is a risk that Disclosure etc. will cause significant hindrance to the proper conduct of our business
    
    *   Cases where Disclosure etc. would violate other laws and regulations
    
    *   Cases in which the individual cannot be identified based on personal identification information, etc.
    
    *   Other cases as required by laws and regulations

Correction, addition, or deletion of Personal Data and suspension of Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Customers etc. may request that we to correct, add, or delete your Personal Data (“Correction etc.”), or stop providing their Personal Data to third parties, in accordance with laws and regulations in the following cases:

*   If the content of Personal Data is different from the facts and the User requests Correction etc. of the Personal Data

*   If we are providing information to a third party without the customer’s consent or without satisfying the requirements of the law, and the customer wishes us to stop providing such information to the third party.

Ceasing to Use or Deleting Personal Data
----------------------------------------

When we receive a request from a Customer etc. to discontinue the use or erase (“Use Cease etc.”) of Personal Data, if we determine that is necessary to comply with such request in accordance with the APPI or other laws and regulations, we will carry out Use Cease etc. of such Personal Data after confirming the identity of the Customer etc.

Notice of Disclosure etc. to Customers etc.
-------------------------------------------

1.  Upon receiving a request for Disclosure etc., from a Customer etc., we will conduct the necessary investigation without delay after verifying the identity of the Customer etc., and notify the Customer etc. of the results of that investigation.
2.  If we decide not to provide Disclosure etc. on reasonable grounds, such as in the following examples, we will notify the Customer etc. to that effect.
    
    *   Cases where there is no record of such Retained Personal Data or provision to a third party
    
    *   Cases where it is difficult to disclose the information by the method requested by the person in question
3.  The provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall not apply in cases where we are not obligated to provide Disclosure etc. of Personal Information under the APPI or other laws and regulations.

Contact for requests for Disclosure etc.
----------------------------------------

If you wish to make a request for Disclosure etc., please fill in the necessary items on our designated application form, enclose documents necessary for identification, and submit the request using one of the following request methods. Please note that the documents sent to us will not be returned. Further, we will not accept requests made in person at our office.

### Necessary documents

*   Application form [(download URL)](https://policies.pixiv.net/pdf/personal_infomation.pdf)

*   Identification documents

Examples: driver’s license, certificate of residence

### Request methods

*   To request by mail

Please mail by certified mail or other means that leaves a record of delivery. The mailing address is as follows:

Address:

Pixiv Inc.

c/o Personal Information Contact Desk

4-23-5 Sendagaya, Shibuya-ku, Tokyo

*   To request electronically

Please fill out the required information and send using the contact information set forth in the “Contact for Inquiries” section below, attaching the data of the necessary documents.

**Contact for Inquiries**
=========================

If you have any questions or requests regarding this Privacy Policy, please use the following form.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**
==================================

We may revise this Privacy Policy without prior notice to Customers etc. In the event of significant changes, we will notify Customers etc. or publicly announce such changes in a manner prescribed by us.

**Language**
============

In the event of any discrepancy between the Japanese version of this Privacy Policy and any other language version, the Japanese version shall prevail.v

Handling of Cookies etc.
========================

当We may use cookies and similar technologies (“Cookies etc.”) to improve the convenience of Our Services, maintain and improve the quality of Our Services, analyze how Our Services are used, and for other purposes. Users shall agree to the following before using Our Services.

Use of Cookies etc. for authentication purposes
-----------------------------------------------

Our Services use Cookies etc. for automatic account authentication. By logging in using your Pixiv account, you can use the service without entering your account information when moving between pages or logging in a second time.

Use of Cookies etc. for service improvement and analysis purposes
-----------------------------------------------------------------

On our website, we transmit IP addresses, access history, device and application information, network information, and other data to data collection and analysis service providers for the purpose of improving the convenience and quality of the website and maintaining its quality.

If you wish to opt-out, please carry out the procedures after confirming the opt-out page of [the relevant company](https://policies.pixiv.net/en/cookie.html#analysis) and the “Disabling cookies etc.” section of this Privacy Policy.

Use of Cookies etc. for advertising purposes
--------------------------------------------

In order to optimize our delivery of advertisements by, we analyze User activity history on Our Services using cookies, ad identifiers, hashed User information, access history, device and application information, information about the network, and the like. The results of such analysis may be used for our targeted advertisements, which are delivered based on Users’ interests.

Further, Our Services may deliver targeted advertisements using cookies, ad identifiers, etc., from the servers of ad-serving providers contracted by us. In such cases, the ad-serving provider will manage such Cookies etc. in accordance with its own privacy policy.

Please check each company’s privacy policy [<here>](https://policies.pixiv.net/en/cookie.html)

If you wish to opt-out, please carry out the procedures after confirming the opt-out page of the relevant ad-serving provider and the “Disabling cookies etc.” section of this Privacy Policy.

Use of Cookies etc. for the purpose of conducting surveys
---------------------------------------------------------

When we conduct a survey, we send Cookies etc., which do not contain Personal Information, to the company that provides the survey service. If you wish to opt-out, please carry out the procedures after confirming the opt-out page of [the relevant company](https://policies.pixiv.net/en/cookie.html#survey) and the “Disabling cookies etc.” section of this Privacy Policy.

About Google Analytics
----------------------

On part of our website and applications (“Applications”), in order to monitor the status of visits to our website and use of Applications by Customers etc., we use “Google Analytics,” a service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”).

When you use our website, Google collects, records, and analyzes your visits to our website based on cookies issued by us. We will receive the results of this analysis from Google to understand the status of visits to our website by Customers etc.

The information collected, recorded, and analyzed by Google Analytics does not contain any information that identifies Customers etc. as specific individuals, and therefore does not constitute “Personal Information” under the APPI. Such information will be managed by Google in accordance with its privacy policy.

o configure your settings for Google Analytics on our website, please see below.

*   If you wish to stop the collection of information about yourself

Please disable Google Analytics in your browser’s add-on settings.

*   If you wish to disable Google Analytics

Please download and install the “Google Analytics Opt-Out Add-on” from the Google Opt-Out Add-on Download Page and change the add-on settings in your browser.

Opt-out add-on:

If you disable Google Analytics, it will also be disabled on other websites, but you can re-enable Google Analytics in your browser’s add-on settings.

For Google Analytics Terms of Use and Google’s Privacy Policy, please refer to the following websites:

Google Analytics Terms of Use:/p>

[https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/)

Google Privacy Policy:

Google Analytics cannot be disabled for the Application. When using the Application, please be aware that usage status will be obtained by Google Analytics.

About reCAPTCHA Enterprise
--------------------------

We have adopted Google’s reCAPTCHA Enterprise service to protect our website from spam submitted to forms on the Internet.

Google collects other data, including IP addresses, from your browser with reCAPTCHA Enterprise in accordance with Google’s [About the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/7687725?hl=en). The data collected is used to determine whether you are a human or a robot.

If you reside in the European Economic Area, which consists of the member states of the European Union, Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein (hereinafter collectively referred to as the “EEA”), your IP address will be anonymized in advance. If you reside in the United States, your IP address will be anonymized in advance. If you reside in the United States of America, your IP address will be anonymized after it has been sent to Google.

In addition, while Google uses the data collected by reCAPTCHA Enterprise to evaluate our website based on User usage, we do not associate such data with any other data held by Google.

Disabling cookies etc.
----------------------

We may use Cookies etc. in Our Services to collect certain information. Depending on the browser you use, you may be able to change its settings to disable Cookies etc., but you may become unable to use all or part of Our Services.

For information on how to configure cookies, please refer to the following URL:

Disabling targeted advertising on Pixiv

Advertising Disablement by DDAI (Data Driven Advertising Initiative)

Ad Disable by YourAdChoices

Disabling web beacons
---------------------

### When web beacons are included in Our Services

Please try the method described in the “Disabling cookies etc.” section of this Article.

### Web beacons are included in DMs and other e-mails

Try disabling the downloading of images contained in e-mails you receive. However, since this depends on the capabilities of the e-mail software you are using, if you are unable to disable it, please unsubscribe from any newsletters to which you are subscribed or set your preferences to block the receipt of such newsletters.

Disabling Cookies etc. (disabling targeted advertising) in iOS applications
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

For instructions on how to disable personalized ads delivered by Apple, please check the following link:

How to manage ad IDs in Android applications
--------------------------------------------

Google Play has introduced Ad IDs for applications to allow Google Users to control their advertising settings. See below for information on how to manage Ad IDs.

For California Residents
========================

This Article (For California Residents) applies to Users and transaction counterparties who are residents of the State of California (hereinafter in this Article, “you”, “your”, etc.).

We handle your Personal Information appropriately in accordance with the California Consumer Privacy Act (2018) of 2020 (CCPA), and the following details the types and categories of such Personal Information that we have collected or disclosed in the past 12 months.

For the purpose of this Article, “Personal Information” means information that identifies a specific individual or household and can be reasonably associated or linked to them.

(1) Our collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information
---------------------------------------------------------------

### a. Types of Personal Information we have collected in the past 12 months

1.  **Identifiers**

Examples: contact information such as name and address, online identifier (IP address), e-mail address, account name, other similar identifiers, cookies, beacons?, mobile advertising identifiers or similar technologies?, customer numbers, unique pseudonyms or User IDs, telephone numbers, or persistent or probabilistic identifiers that can be used to recognize a specific consumer or device?, UserAgent.

3.  **Personal information as defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act**

Examples: contact information such as name and address, partial credit or debit card payment numbers, PayPal account, education, school name, employment, employment history, bank information such as account numbers, etc.

5.  **Protected classifications under California or federal law**

Examples: gender, age, date of birth,

7.  **Commercial information**

Examples: transaction information, purchase history, financial details, payment information, etc.; records of personal property; records of products or services purchased, acquired, or considered; and records of other purchases or consumption history or trends.

9.  **Biometric Information**

Examples: face, hands, voice recording, video.

11.  **Information on Internet or other electronic network activities**

Examples: browsing history, online behavior, interactions with our and other websites, and other Internet or network activity history.

13.  **Geolocation data**

Examples: IP location information, etc.

15.  Audio, electronic, visual, and similar information, including images and sound recordings, telephone calls, and video recordings made in connection with our business activities and transaction counterparties.
16.  **Occupational or employment information, such as employment history, past employers, etc.**

Not obtained.

18.  **Academic records and other educational information subject to the U.S. Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act**

Not obtained.

20.  **Information inferred from the above Personal Information, for example, to create a profile or summary of an individual’s preferences or personality**
     
     Action history (page transition history), browsing history, purchase history

### b.Purpose of use of collected information

Please refer to the [“Purposes of Use”](#purposes_of_use) section of this Privacy Policy for the purposes for which we use the information we collect from you.

### c. Sources of collected information

The sources of the information we collect are as follows:

*   Information entered by you at the time of account creation, etc.

*   IP addresses, etc. obtained by us when you visit our website.

### d. Sharing of collected information

Please refer to the [“Sharing of Personal Data”](#sharing_of_personal_data) section of this Privacy Policy regarding with whom we share collected information.

### e. Types of Personal Information disclosed in the past 12 months and to whom

We have disclosed the Personal Information of A, B, and D in “a. Types of Personal Information we have collected in the past 12 months” to third parties in “d. Sharing of collected information” for the purpose of conducting our business.

### f. Past/future sales, opt-out from sales

We have not sold any Personal Information (including Personal Information of minors) for a period of 12 months prior to the effective date of this Privacy Policy.

For purposes of this Article, “sold” or “sales” means “disclosing Personal Information for monetary or other valuable consideration”; provided, however, that “sold” or “sales” does not include, for example, the transfer of Personal Information as part of the assets of a merger, bankruptcy, or transfer of all or part of our business.

(2) Customer rights and requests to us
--------------------------------------

### a. Right to request disclosure of information and deletion of information

1.  If you are a consumer or resident of the State of California, you may make requests to us for:

(i) Disclosure of information

You may request that we disclose the following information to you, provided that the information is from within 12 months of the date of the request

*   The types of Personal Information we collect about you

*   The types of sources from which we collect your Personal Information

*   The business or commercial purposes for which we collect your Personal Information

*   The types of your Personal Information, and the types of third parties to which we share or disclose your Personal Information, in the event that we share or disclose your Personal Information to third parties

(ii) Deletion of information

You may request that we delete your Personal Information that we have collected or obtained from you.

10.  We will respond to your request as described in the preceding paragraph in accordance with applicable laws and regulations; provided, however, that we may deny your request in cases where the relevant laws and regulations do not apply or where an exception applies.

### b. Procedures for disclosure and deletion of customer information

Please refer to the [“Procedures for Requests Regarding Personal Data and Records of Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties”](#personal_data_to_third_parties) section of this Privacy Policy for the procedures for requesting disclosure and deletion of customer information.

### c. Right not to be discriminated against

We will not unfairly discriminate against you because you exercise any rights under the CCPA.

### d. Other privacy rights in California (“Do Not Track”)

At this time, our website and applications cannot accommodate “Do Not Track” requests. Please note that we may use tracking technology to collect Personal Information, including your activity history, when you use Our Services. Please refer to the [Handling of Cookies etc.”](#handling_of_coolies) section of this Privacy Policy for more information.

### e. Contact information for questions or concerns

If you have any questions regarding this Article, please use the contact information in the [“Contact for Inquiries”](https://policies.pixiv.net/en/contact_for_inquiries) section of this Privacy Policy.

For EU Residents
================

This Article (For EU Residents) applies to Users and transaction counterparties who reside within the EEA (European Economic Area consisting of the EU Member States, Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein) (hereinafter in this Article, “you”, “your”, etc.).

We will handle your Personal Data (as defined in (1), b. of this Article) appropriately in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as set forth below.

In this Article, “Personal Data” means “information about an identified or identifiable natural person (data subject).”

(1) Obtainment and retention of Personal Data
---------------------------------------------

1.  Method of obtainment

We obtain Personal Data in the following ways

*   Directly from you (e.g., when you enter your information when creating an account)

*   Indirectly from you (e.g., by obtaining the IP address when you visit our website)

5.  Types of Personal Data acquired or retained

In this Article, the types of User Data that acquired or retained refers to items (1) through (4) of the [“Scope of this Privacy Policy and User Data Obtained”](#scope_of_this_privacy_policy) section of this Privacy Policy.

(2) Purposes of use of Personal Data
------------------------------------

Please refer to the [“Purposes of Use”](#purposes_of_use) section of this Privacy Policy for the purposes for which we use the Personal Data we obtain from you.

(3) Legal basis
---------------

1.  We process Personal Data on the following legal basis
    
    *   Your agreement to this Privacy Policy
    
    *   Necessity for us to fulfill various agreements with you
    
    *   Necessity for us to carry out various procedures requested by you
2.  You have the right to choose whether or not to provide us with your Personal Data, but if you do not provide us with your Personal Data, you may not receive Our Services.

(4) Retention period of Personal Data
-------------------------------------

We store Personal Data only for the period of time necessary to achieve the purposes of use stated in “(2) Purposes of Use of Personal Data” in this Article or for the period of time stipulated by laws and regulations, etc. We promptly erase such Personal Data after the retention period has elapsed.

(5) Personal data to be shared
------------------------------

Please refer to the [“Sharing of Personal Data”](#sharing_of_personal_data) section of this Privacy Policy for information on the sharing of Personal Data.

(6) Provision of Personal Data to third parties
-----------------------------------------------

We may provide Personal Data obtained from you to third parties within the scope of the [“Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties”](#provision_of_personal_data_to_third_parties) section of this Privacy Policy.

(7) Overseas transfer of Personal Data
--------------------------------------

We may transfer Personal Data to third countries (countries that have been certified as sufficient by the European Commission or companies that adhere to equivalent standards) in compliance with various laws and regulations for the following purposes (for details, see the [“Provision of Personal Data to Third Parties”](#provision_of_personal_data_to_third_parties) and [“Handling of Cookies etc.”](#handling_of_cookies) sections in this Privacy Policy).

*   To provide Our Services

*   To comply with procedures requested by customers

(8) Your rights to your Personal Data
-------------------------------------

You have the right to withdraw your consent to the use of your Personal Data and the right to access, correct, erase, restrict processing, exercise data portability and object to the processing of your Personal Data.

You may also object to the processing of your Personal Data to us or to the data protection authority having jurisdiction over your location.

(9) Accuracy and security of Personal Data
------------------------------------------

In order to achieve “(2) Purposes of use of Personal Data”, we will maintain the Personal Data in our possession accurate and up-to-date by taking security measures in accordance with the [“Security Control Systems”](#security_control_systems) section of this Privacy Policy.

(10) Automatic handling of Personal Data
----------------------------------------

Personal data we collect may be subject to automatic handling, such as profiling, in analytical and recommendation functions for Users.

(11) Handling of cookies etc.
-----------------------------

For more information on Cookies etc., please refer to the [“Handling of Cookies etc.”](#handling_of_cookies) and [“Disabling cookies etc.”](#disabling_cookies) sections in this Privacy Policy.

(12) Revision of this Article
-----------------------------

We may revise this Article without notice to customers. Please refer to the [“Changes to this Privacy Policy”](#change_to_this_privacy_policy) section of this Privacy Policy regarding any revisions to this Article.

(13) Contact for inquiries
--------------------------

For any questions regarding this Article (For EU Residents), please use the contact information in the [“Contact for Inquiries”](#contact_for_inquiries) section of this Privacy Policy.

Revision History
================

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Revision date | Content of revision |
| March 5, 2025 | Address updated due to building name change. |
| May 28, 2024 | Maintenance and overall organization of the display in order to make it compliant with Japanese law and overseas laws and regulations (CCPA, GDPR) |
| May 31st, 2024 | Development of descriptions for GDPR and other foreign laws and the overall organization that goes along with it. |
| August 31st, 2023 | “Article 3. Information Company acquires and purposes of use (according to each Service)” and “Article 5. Provision of Personal Information to third parties, etc.” were updated. |
| June 13th, 2023 | Revised “Article 14. Use of cookies, advertising identifiers, ID solutions, etc.” in accordance with the updated Telecommunications Business Act (Japanese law), regarding external disclosure of information. |
| July 28th, 2022 | Revised “procedures and methods” for “Article 3. Information the Company acquires and purposes of use”, “Article 5. Provision of Personal Information to third parties, etc.”, “Article 6. Information input by Users for the purposes of credit card payments on the Services”, and “Article 7. Disclosure, Correction, etc.”. |
| July 7th, 2022 | Revised “Article 14. Use of cookies, advertising identifiers, ID solutions, etc.”. |
| May 31st, 2021 | To optimize payment options and advertising distribution, revised and added elements to the following: “Article 3. Information the Company acquires and purposes of use”, “Article 5. Provision of Personal Information to third parties, etc.”, “Article 6. Information input by Users for the purposes of credit card payments on the Services”, “13. Use of cookies, advertising identifiers, ID solutions, etc.”, and “Article 17. Personal Information Handling Business Operator”. |
| December 1st, 2020 | In accordance with the retiring of the pixivPAY service, removed “2. Pay” from “2. Individual services” under “Article 3. Information the Company acquires and purposes of use (according to each Service)”. |
| March 30th, 2020 | Revised all Individual Terms of Use to be in accordance with the revisions to the pixiv Inc. Service Master Terms of Use. |
| April 18th, 2019 | Updated usage status verification and service improvement inquiries related to the use of reCAPTCHA by adding reCAPTCHA to “Article 13. Use of cookies, advertising identifiers, ID solutions, etc.”. |
| September 12th, 2018 | Updated company information in accordance with the addition of company advertising: addition of company name and link to company advertisements falling under “Article 13. Use of cookies, advertising identifiers, ID solutions, etc.”. |
| May 16th, 2018 | In accordance with the enactment of the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), revised “Article 13. Use of cookies, advertising identifiers, ID solutions, etc.” to give a clearer explanation of the purpose of data use (login, usage status, advertising, etc.) and more clearly explain data use methods, invalidation procedures, etc. |
